# Miguel Angel Ricaño

## **FULL STACK DEVELOPER**

**SUMMARY** 

Full Stack Developer with a great love of building apps to solve today's problems. Skilled in the arts of organization, negotiation, and mediation. A strong believer in clean code and user experience, fluent in multiple languages, frameworks, and technologies, and capable of ramping up quickly and efficiently.

### **EXPERIENCE**

Globant, Remote

Ruby Developer SSr | February 2022 - Present

• I'm part of the first backend team for the new client Food52.

Technologies: Ruby, Ruby on Rails, GraphQL, Postgresql

Agency LA, Remote

Full Stack Developer | September 2021 – January 2022

- I concluded the strategic development objectives 2 months before the agreed date.
- Made 2 contributions to RedwoodJS open source on behalf of Agency.
- I finished 4 new integrations to be prepared to open in new cities and countries, working with APIs from Cloudinary and Twilio.
- I created over 80 tests for different parts of the frontend with Jasmine and around 10 for the backend.

Technologies: TypeScript, RedwoodJS, React, Prisma, Postgresql, GraphQL, Doppler

Lisa Insurtech, Remote

Ruby on Rails Developer | April 2021 - September 2021

- I took care of the backend for 2 of 3 repositories owned by the company. These technologies work with microservices.
- I integrated 3 new services into the applications. Which were very welcomed by the clients.
- In the first month at the company, I reduced the average ticket time by 20% for backend development.

Technologies: JavaScript, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Angular, Docker

Microverse, Remote

Code Reviewer | October 2020 - April 2021

 Reviewed 500+ projects for junior developers, assessing front-end and back-ends for projects built in HTML & CSS, Ruby, Rails, and JavaScript.

IK Sustainable, Remote

eCommerce Developer | May 2020 - July 2021

- Learned Liquid in 2 weeks to build the style theme and meet the launch date of the eCommerce.
- Developed 2 apps for the company, including, a size chart and an app that connects to Instagram to display on the front page, increasing conversions and engagement by 2x.
- Achieved 2500+ daily visits due to improvements in SMO and SEO.

Technologies: JavaScript, Ruby, Liquid, HTML/CSS

www.miguelricano.me <u>Github</u> | <u>Linkedin</u> mricanho@gmail.com

#### **SKILLS**

Front-End: JavaScript, TypeScript, React, Redux, Angular, HTML5, CSS3, Bulma, Bootstrap, Tailwind

**Back-End**: Ruby, Rails, PostgreSQL, Liquid

Tools & Methods: Git, GitHub, BitBucket, Gitlab, Heroku, Netlify, Mobile/Responsive Development, RSpec, TDD, Chrome Dev Tools, Docker, GraphQL, Doppler, Linear, StoryBook, Jasmine

**Professional**: Remote Pair-Programming, Teamwork, Mentoring

## **PROJECTS**

### EasyWeather (March-2021)

- EasyWeather is a project to display the temp and weather conditions of the desired city cutely.
- Built with JavaScript, HTML5, Bulma.
- -Repository <u>here</u>.

### Sustyle (February-2021)

- Website focused on the latest sustainability articles.
- Ruby on Rails, Ruby, Bulma, PostgreSQL.
- -Repository <u>here</u>.

#### Izel (May-2018 - April-2020)

- Website focused on the latest sustainability articles.
- Ruby on Rails, Ruby, PHP, PostgreSQL, JavaScript.

Magma Labs, Remote- Mexico

Freelance Full Stack Developer | April 2020 – September 2020

- For Magma Labs I worked on two projects, Tamex, and Minimal Audio.
- At Tamex, along with another developer, take care of the foreign keys and databases relations between the products, categories, and classes.
- At Minimal Audio, I begin my journey with React and set the scope and models for the business logic.

Technologies: React, Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, Ruby, Stripe Connect

Izel, Xalapa, Mexico

Co-funder, General Manager | February 2018 – April 2020

- I founded IZEL as a way to disrupt the fashion industry and develop Just In Time production methods, using state of the edge technology and a multilevel marketing structure.
- 280 Izel representatives network in all Mexico
- 100K in sales for the first 7 months of operation
- With 2 more developers, we develop a system for the entire operation of the company, since the production of the clothing, the management of the sales force and the logistics of the deliveries.

Technologies: Ruby on Rails, MySQL, Ruby, Conekta, Ember

The Rolland Collection, Bordeaux, France

Business Manager for LATAM and Asia | January 2012 - May 2014

- Awarded a doubling in the size of my team by management, thanks to excellent initial results in the first 6 months of my tenure.
- Increased sales by 30% in Asia and 15% in Latin America in less than a year.

Budhi, Mexico City, Mexico

Founder & Director | August 2010 - November 2011

- Developed Maat software, the first administrative software in the country with a freemium model, built to emulate the decisions of professional admins.
- Managed Budhi's 2011 acquisition by Grupo Carso, including its software "Maat", to add it to GC's catalog of free services for small businesses.

#### **EDUCATION**

Microverse | 2020 - 2021

Remote Full Stack Web Development Program, Full Time

- Spent 1400+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while simultaneously developing projects with Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, and Redux.
- Developed skills in remote pair-programming using GitHub, industry-standard gitflow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.

EBS Paris - European Business School | 2012 –2014

Master of Business Administration, International Business Management (Incomplete)

Universidad Veracruzana | 2005 - 2010

Bachelor of Business Administration, International Business Management

# <u>Tamex (August-2020 - November-2020)</u>

- E-commerce that sells home hardware.
- Ruby on Rails, Ruby, PostgreSQL.
- -Live eCommerce here.

# Minimal Audio (Octuber-2020 - December-2020)

- E-commerce focused on selling audio tracks.
- Ruby on Rails, Ruby Hotwire, PostgreSQL, React.
- -Live eCommerce here.

#### **VOLUNTEER**

Mentor, Microverse As a volunteer mentor, I help junior developers understand and develop in the new and demanding Microverse work environment.

English-Spanish Translator, RedwoodJS

#### **LANGUAGES**

Spanish, Native English, C1 French, B1 German, A2